# **Trevor Jordan**

(804) 513-2340 · tsj7ww@gmail.com · LinkedIn · GitHub

# **Objective**

An experienced analyst with a passion for solving problems through statistical analysis and data engineering. I have the analytical background, problem solving knowledge and communication skills it takes to lead positive change in any organization.

### **Experience**

#### **Capital One**

Senior Business Analyst Apr 2021 – Present

- · Worked in Bank Loss Mitigation defining strategy and execution for reducing losses across various financial products.
- · Reduced calling costs by 30% without increased losses by identifying ineffective calls on delinquent customers during analysis of customer behavior using account and transaction data, including a KPI monitoring plan to mitigate risk.
- Enabled call center operations to proactively and efficiently staff by building volume forecasts and capacity plans using regression models for prediction and contingency planning to handle unanticipated changes.
- Estimated the expected financial impact of significant technology changes on business operations by observing historical trends and evaluating potential revenue gains and missed opportunities.
- · Assessed and proposed analytical projects to enterprise risk management during yearly program evaluation meetings used to set direction of bank loss mitigation strategy.

Senior Data Analyst Mar 2019 – Apr 2021

- · Worked in Bank Operations on a team of 20+ analysts focused on automation and reporting to improve efficiency.
- · Built KPI dashboards generating actionable training opportunities and strategy changes for call center operations managers by providing core metrics on call efficiency and performance using Tableau.
- · Increased accuracy, consistency and granularity of analysis by building a data mart which consolidated over 20 data sources and incorporated extensive business logic, resulting in over 2k lines of SQL code.
- Reduced time and friction of regulatory audits by designing policies to increase transparency of analytical projects and leading implementation across bank operations analyst teams.
- Enhanced data quality and availability by building automated data pipelines to clean, supplement and transport terabytes of data from AWS S3 into data warehouses using Python and Apache Spark.

#### Compare.com

Data Analyst Apr 2018 – Mar 2019

- · Worked on a small team of analysts and was the sole analyst supporting marketing strategy and operations.
- · Identified optimal customer segments for customer acquisition by maximizing conversion rates based on specific customer attributes using a multivariate linear regression model.
- · Reallocated \$1.2M yearly marketing spend from underperforming geographical regions by analyzing financial performance metrics using heat maps with Tableau.
- · Established real-time marketing performance monitoring by building KPI dashboards in collaboration with team managers using Tableau.

## **Skills**

- · Analysis: Inferential Statistics, Predictive Modeling, Time-Series Analysis, Forecasting, Machine Learning, Operations Research
- **Technology**: SQL, Python, Tableau, Excel, Linux, AWS (S3, Lambda, EC2, DynamoDB, Redshift, QuickSight), Apache (Spark, Hadoop, Airflow)
- · Business: Problem Solving, Project Management, Communication, Storytelling
- Certifications: AWS Data Analytics Specialty (Nov 2020), AWS Solutions Architect Associate (Sep 2020)

#### **Education**

#### B.A. in Economics | University of Virginia

May 2017

- · Achievements: Distinguished Majors Program, Concentration in Industrial Organization
- · Coursework: Mathematical Statistics, Multivariate Calculus, Linear Algebra, Probability, Econometrics II